# **Christopher Barcala**

10043 41st Ave SW, Seattle, WA 98116 chrisbarcala@gmail.com • Mobile: 206.890.1407 <u>Linkedin Profile - Portfolio - GitHub</u>

Accomplished Client Systems Engineer with 14 years' experience providing outstanding customer service to a variety of external and internal customers including Software Development using Filemaker, System Center Service Manager and ServiceNow. Looking to focus more on working with Customers on the Development side.

# **Professional Experience**

IT Client Systems Engineer – FTE / Sound Transit / Seattle, WA

May 2017 - Present

- Provide support and serve as a point of escalation for Macs, PC's, iOS and Android Tablets agency wide.
- Office 365 Exchange Administration and Troubleshooting including usage of PowerShell commands to access advanced administration features.
- Created and Documented PowerShell scripts for my team to automate the creation of Resource Rooms and Shared Calendars with default settings not available in the Admin Center GUI.
- Created Documentation on necessary day to day Office 365 Exchange PowerShell Scripts for my team.
- Created a PowerShell Script to run through Active Directory OU's and perform a cleanup on Telephone and IP Phone fields for the Cisco Jabber rollout.
- Created a 365 PowerShell Script that runs daily in order to enforce Calendar permissions to all users Agency Wide while logging out any changes made. Built with the ability to include/exclude users via AD Security Groups.
- Architecting and engineering JAMF Pro to support the Apple environment more efficiently.
- Member of the ServiceNow Admin Team helping build Service Requests with the Launch.
- Creation of Javascript Ajax calls for Client Side Scripting in ServiceNow.
- Worked with both internal IT and external teams to gather requirements and build new workflows that will improve the efficiency of their requests.
- Configuring new Email notifications within Service Manager that require knowledge of HTML.
- Documented all System Center Service Manager procedures on creating new workflows, troubleshooting, server upgrades, and configuring settings.
- Documented all newly created Workflows as a record of changes in Service Manager.

### Client Systems Administrator – Contract / Sound Transit / Seattle, WA

March 2016 - May 2017

- Provide support and maintenance of Macs, iOS Devices and Android Tablets as a primary point of contact for the Creative Services and IT Development department.
- Advise and manage software and hardware updates for Macs including tracking AppleCare Warranty.
- Utilize Airwatch MDM to manage and deploy mobile devices throughout Agency.
- Provide a point of escalation for Service Desk for Active Directory, Office 365, general troubleshooting.
- Develop Knowledge Base articles related to Mac, iOS and Android support for Analysts and End Users.
- Provided basic support for System Center Service Manager with self-education and research.
- Provide outstanding customer support to end users and coworkers providing accurate feedback on technical problems and coordination communications between client and information technology staff.

#### IT Consultant / Machattan Inc / New York, NY

2008 - 2016

- Managed all desktop and server support, wireless and wired networks, printing, audio/visual, inventory, security, digital asset management, On-site and Off-site backups, and yearly project deployments.
- Provided insightful and friendly support to multiple clients, taking absolute responsibility as the point of

- contact for each, while earning clients trust due to my patience and empathy.
- Provided onsite, face-to-face expertise and training to Users, Partners and CEOs.
- Continued my Filemaker Developer role to work with various clients with the creation of new and troubleshooting of existing Filemaker Databases. Took ownership of each project as the sole Filemaker Developer in my company. Gathered requirements from different departments at each client to continue to revamp their databases.
- Advised, supported and managed all client/server projects including Software/Hardware rollouts and upgrades.
- Performed email migrations from Gmail to Hosted Exchange and vice versa.
- Collaborated with multiple vendors for all equipment and services including printers, telephones, ISP, email.
- Provided On-site Apple Certified Hardware Repairs as an Apple Certified Mac Technician.

## Client Systems Administrator / Hirschhorn & Young Graphics / New York, NY

2003 - 2008

- Provided support of all levels for all users and equipment including Servers, Networking and Backups.
- Took self-initiative to learn and become the in-house Filemaker Developer along with my other duties. Managed existing databases and developed all new projects using Filemaker Pro by gathering requirements from various teams. The Filemaker Database was crucial for the day-to-day ticketing, asset inventory and timesheet system of the company.
- Maintained all aspects of technology including printing, software deployment, telecommunications, audio/visual, inventory, digital asset management, font licensing, backups and servers.

#### **Education/Certification**

Herbert H. Lehman College, New York

Bachelor of Computer Science (2001)

Minor in Computer Graphics

Honors: Golden Key National Honor Society, Dean's List, Scholar-Athlete

Automating Administration with Windows Powershell – 2017
Enabling and Managing Office 365 - 2017
ITIL v3 Certification – 2018
University of Washington Full Stack Development Coding Bootcamp – 2019

### **Skills**

**Software:** Microsoft Windows 7/8/10, Microsoft Windows Server 2012, Mac OS X and OS X Server, iOS, Android, Active Directory Administration, PowerShell, VMWare Airwatch MDM, FTP/SFTP, Microsoft Office Suite, Office 365 Exchange, System Center Configuration Manager, Filemaker Pro, System Center Service Manager, ServiceNow Administration

Software Development: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, jQuery, Ajax, Node.js, Git, Responsive Design